Antonio Alonso Dominguez

Software Engineer

Profile

Highly experienced Software Engineer specialised on backend platforms with solid foundations on architecture, distributed computing and full software product lifecycle.

After 10 years using *traditional* OOP, over the last 4 years I became a **functional programmer advocate and mentor** after having the chance to successfully put into production several services using FP principles while training other engineers.

Experience

Detailed

2019-now Technical Leader, WeJo.com, Manchester, UK, Contractor.

Product Adept

2016–2019 Principal Software Engineer, Rentalcars.com/Booking.com, Manchester, UK.

Data & Reporting department

Achievements:

- Built from the ground up two real-time analytics platforms using Lamda Architecture:
 - A customer-centric segmentation platform for customer personalisation purposes.
 - A framework and backend for multi-variant testing of our front-end, in which hundreds of A/B experiments are run on a daily basis.
- Re-engineered for scalability a big chunk of our taxi service **Rideways.com** (now Booking Taxis) prior to our fusion with Booking.com so it could handle the upcoming load.
- Introduced the practice of *mob programming* as a way of creating a cohesive team and upskilling quickly the members with some experience gap in relation to the senior members.
- Successfully mentoured several developers into Scala and functional programming.

2015–2016 **Software Team Leader**, Rentalcars.com, Manchester, UK.

Communications Platform

Achievements:

- No more outages. This platform used to have severe outages every single week, which were extremelly costly. This was achieved by:
 - Removing queues, we changed it from having 25 different queues to just 2.
 - Re-design the data model, which was stored in Couchbase, so the operation of the platform would produce less object mutations and therefore trigger compaction less often.
 - Used lock-free asynchronous (reactive) programming for streamlining the IO work.
 - Deleting loads of code, seriously, we had a 75% of code duplication at the start.
- Reduced cost of operation by moving from bare metal to virtualized environment.
- As a by-product, we got a 3x throughput increase and ability to handle a load at least 10 times bigger than the standard operation.
- First project in the company using an agile methodology and techniques like pair programming and TDD.

2014–2015 Senior Software Engineer, Nektan, London, UK.

Real Money Gaming Platform

Achievements:

- Building the new gaming platform as a series of RESTful microservices, enabling integrations with other casino providers.
- Built the testing platform for running game simulations and verification of expected game outcomes.

Summarized

2012–2014 **Senior Software Engineer**, *Magnetise Group*, London, UK, Contractor.

Lead Generation Platform

2011–2012 **Application Architect**, *GE Capital*, Manchester, UK, Contractor.

GE Fleet - Quote To Install Platform

2010–2011 Senior Software Engineer, Indra Software Labs, A Coruña, Spain.

Gas Natural CRM

2007–2010 **Software Engineer**, *Softek GDC Europe*, A Coruña, Spain.

Several Positions

2005–2007 **Software Engineer**, *Interlogical Data Systems*, A Coruña, Spain.

FERE Resource Planning Platform

Education

2004–2006 NVQ 4 - Software Engineering, IES Fernando Writz, A Coruña, Spain, First Grade.

Skills

Architecture Lambda Architecture, CQRS, Event-

Plaforms Kubernetes, Docker, Hadoop, AWS

Sourcing

Programming Scala, Haskell, Python, Go

Frameworks Akka, cats/scalaz, Apache Spark,

Servant, Distributed Process

Databases MySQL, Couchbase, DynamoDB,

Middleware Kafka, Kinesis, RabbitMQ

Hive, Impala

Methodologies Scrum, Kanban, Event-Storming Practises Continuous Delivery, TDD, Pair &

Mob Programming

Languages

Spanish Native

Galician Native

Italian B1

Personal Projects

cron4s Scala CRON parser

https://alonsodomin.github.io/cron4s

scala-colog Scala pure functional logging

https://alonsodomin.github.io/scala-colog

hschema Haskell Schema Definitions

https://github.com/alonsodomin/haskell-schema

sbt-spark SBT plugin for configuring Apache Spark applications

https://github.com/alonsodomin/sbt-spark